Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee Secretary of the University Records, 1907-2014
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
UW-Milwaukee Secretary of the University Records, 1907-2014
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. Secretary of the University
UWM Archival Collection 152
Accession 2011-002
Accession 2016-009
Accession 2016-019
1.4 cubic ft. (2 boxes) plus additions of 12.6 cubic ft. (14 boxes) and 85.5 MB (6953 digital files)
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Collection contains the records of the Secretary of the University for the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. The records include correspondence and memos; general committee information; and information pertaining to the general services of the campus, such as telephone and mail service. The collection contains copies of deeds to several UWM properties, including the deeds to Engelmann Hall, Purin Hall, and the sight of Mitchell Hall. The records also contain a survey regarding campus space, information on the properties UWM rented, and the allotment of space. More recent accessions contain materials relating to Senate Faculty meetings (minutes, agendas, documents) from 1956-2003, miscellaneous correspondence, policy development for UWM faculty and staff, and background information on award recipients (Spaights Plaza awards and honorary degrees). There are also restricted files regarding tenture meetings and decisions of faculty members.
The office of the Secretary of the University was established in 1956 under the title of Secretary of the Faculty. The duties performed by the secretary included: arranging and publishing committee information, collecting and preserving appropriate records of the committees, acting as the secretary to several committees, supervising general services, and assigning space. In 1974 the title of the office was changed to the Secretary of the University.
Secretaries
1956-1959 Theodore J. McLaughlin
1959-1961 William A. Jenkins
1961-1966 Joseph W. Kenny
1966-1968 Irving Anti
1968-1974 Burton Pottervel
1974-1982 John J. Solon
1982-1997 Marilyn E. Miller
1997-1999 George S. Baker
1999-2003 Ellen K. Murphy
2003-2004 Vacant
2004-2006 Randall Ryder (Interim)
2006-2008 Randall Ryder
2008- Trudy Turner
This collection was received in, and is organized in, multiple parts. Additional materials have not been physically or intellectually arranged and interfiled, and researchers may need to consult more than one part of the collection to locate similar materials.
UWM Archival Collection 152: Records, 1907-2014
The collection contains three additional accessions.
Accession 2011-002: Search and Screen Committee Materials, 2010-2011
Accession 2016-009: Governance Files, 1956-2010
Accession 2016-019: Governance Files, 1961-2009
Related Material in the UWM Libraries
UW-Milwaukee Buildings Blueprint Collection UWM Archival Collection 50
UW-Milwaukee Campus Committees Collection UWM Archival Collection 121
UW-Milwaukee Department of Planning and Construction, Office of the Director Records UWM Archival Collection 118
UW-Milwaukee Faculty Senate Records UWM Archival Collection 151
UW-Milwaukee Office of the Chancellor Records UWM Archival Collection 46
UW-Milwaukee Physical Environment Committee Records UWM Archival Collection 120
Administrative/Restriction Information
As of January 5, 2017, all electronic files were accessible on a Intel Core i5-4570 CPU (3.20 GHz, 4 GB RAM) running Windows 7 Enterprise, with Service Pack 1. Software used to access the files includes Microsoft Office 2007, LibreOffice Writer, Firefox v. 21.0, and Adobe Reader XI. The collection includes records in the following file formats:
Microsoft Word Document 97-2003 [.doc]
Microsoft Word for Windows 2007 onwards [.docx]
Hypertext Markup Language [.html]
Acrobat PDF 1.2-1.6 - Portable Document Format [.pdf]
Microsoft Powerpoint Document [.ppt]
Rich Text Format [.rtf]
Plain Text File [.txt]
WordPerfect for MS-DOS/Windows Document 4-7 [.wpd]
Microsoft Works Word Processor 5-6 [.wps]
Microsoft Excel 97 Workbook [.xls]
Electronic records must be viewed in the archives. See an archivist for more information.
Accession 2011-002, boxes 1-2 of Accession 2016-009, the divisional committee and grievance folders in the electronic files, and boxes 5-7 of Accession 2016-019 are restricted under UWM's Personnel File Policy.Consult an archivist for details.
There are no access restrictions on the rest of the materials, and the collection is open to all members of the public in accordance with state law.
An unknown individual transferred the collection to the Archives prior to 1989. The office of the Secretary transferred additional records in September 1998 (accession 1998-018) and October 1998 (accession 1998-029). Mark Schwartz, the Search and Screen Committee Chair, donated additional materials in July 2011 (accession 2011-002). The office of the Secretary transferred additional records in fall 2016 (accessions 2016-009 and 2016-019).
Contents List
- Records, 1907-2014, UWM Archival Collection 152; 1.4 cubic ft. (2 boxes)
  - Annual Reports, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Campus Building Chairpersons and Hours, 1980-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Committee Information, 1958-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Memos, 1956-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
  - Deeds to University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Property, 1907-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Divisional Memberships, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Faculty and Academic Staff Payroll, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Faculty and Staff Statistics, 1962-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Documents, 1957-2014
    Records captured as part of UWM Web Collection.
  - General Services, 1958-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Institutional Research, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memorial Resolutions, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - News and Events, 2013-2014
  - Nomination and Election Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Nominations Committee, 1990-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - North Central Association Steering Committee Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Planning Documents, 1980-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Property Holdings of the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Registration Procedures and Proposals, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Rental Property, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Secretary of the Faculty, 1957-1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Secretary of the University, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Space Allocation, 1958-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - Space Survey Book A, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Space Survey Book B, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
  - Subcommittee on Names and Buildings, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Summary of Budget, UWM, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - University of Wisconsin - Wisconsin State University Merger, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - UWM Policies and Procedures, 1976-1992 (Box 1, Folder 28-31)
  - Veterans' Advisory Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Search and Screen Committee Materials, 2010-2011, Accession 2011-002; 342 digital files; Additions of search and screen committee materials, dating from 2010 to 2011.
- Governance Files, 1956-2010, Accession 2016-009; 5.6 cubic ft. (7 boxes) 85 MB (6611 digital files); Additions of physical records include faculty Senate meeting materials (documents, calendars/agendas, and minutes); miscellaneous Secretary correpsondence; memorial resolutions; schedule of classes and exams. Digital files include various university committees (Academic Staff, Senate, Divisional, Faculty Senate) materials and other miscellaneous contents.
  - Academic Staff Committee, 1990-2001
  - Academic Staff Senate, 1992-2002
  - Correspondence and New Faculty Lists, 1956-2010 (Box 1)
    Restricted
  - Divisional Committees
    - 1993-2001
    - Minutes and Agendas, 1974-2008 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Senate
    - 1990-2003
    - Calendars, Documents, Minutes
      - 1962-1971 (Box 3)
      - 1970-1979 (Box 4)
      - 1978-1989 (Box 5)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - General Files, 1993-2002
  - Grievance Committees, 1994-2007
  - Memorial Resolutions; Schedules of Classes and Exams 1982-1992 (Box 7)
  - Standing Committees, 1995-2003
  - University Committee, 1994-2001
- Governance Files,1961-2009, Accession 2016-019; 7 cubic ft. (7 boxes); Additions of Honorary Degrees and Spaights Plaza Awards; UWM policies, procedures, rules and regulations; criteria and format for tenure organized by divisional committees (Arts & Humanities, Natural Sciences, Professions, and Social Sciences); and tenure meeting materials and decisions organized by divisional committees.
  - Honorary Degrees and Spaights Plaza Awards, 1983-2008 (Box 1)
  - Spaights Plaza Awards and UWM Policies and Procedures, 1981-2009 (Box 2)
  - Divisional Committees
    - Arts and Humanities and Professions Tenure Decisions, 1993-2009 (Box 5)
    - Criteria and Format Guidelines For Tenure, 1969-2008 (Box 4)
    - Natural Sciences and Social Sciences Tenure Decisions, 1996-2004 (Box 6)
    - Professions Tenure Decisions, 1995-2001 (Box 7)
  - UWM Policies, Procedures, Rules and Regulations, 1961-2008 (Box 3)